{
    "question": "572)\uf020 Name the joint maritime exercise that was held by\nnavies of India, US and Japan, off the coast of\nJapan from Sept 27 to Oct 4",
    "answer": " Malabar\n"
}{
    "question": "573)\uf020 Name the winner of this year's SASTRA\nRamanujan Prize",
    "answer": " Adam Harper, England\n"
}{
    "question": "574)\uf020 World Rivers Day is observed on which Sunday of\nSeptember",
    "answer": " 4th\n"
}{
    "question": "575)\uf020 Which international day promotes preventative\nmeasures to reduce the risk of cardiovascular\ndiseases (CVDs)",
    "answer": " World Heart Day, Sept 29\n"
}{
    "question": "577)\uf020 What is the name of the civilian award to be given\nfor promoting unity and integrity of India",
    "answer": " Sardar\nPatel Unity Award\n"
}{
    "question": "578)\uf020 Name the noted economist from Bulgaria who has\nbeen selected as the new head of the IMF",
    "answer": "\nKristalina Georgieva\n"
}{
    "question": "579)\uf020 ________ has become the first state to distribute the\nhighest number of golden cards under Ayushman\nBharat",
    "answer": " J & K\n"
}{
    "question": "580)\uf020 The Indian Navy\u2019s biggest dry dock with\ncapacityto accommodate an aircraft carrier was\ninaugurated recently at which place",
    "answer": " Mumbai\n"
}{
    "question": "581)\uf020 Which naval force commissioned the offshore\npatrol vessel (OPV) \u2018Varaha\u2019",
    "answer": " Indian Coast Guard\n"
}{
    "question": "582)\uf020 Name the veteran actor honoured with this year's\nDada Saheb Phalke award",
    "answer": " Amitabh Bachchan\n"
}{
    "question": "583)\uf020 What is the amount of cash prize given in the\nDada Saheb Phalke award",
    "answer": " Rs. 10 lakh\n"
}{
    "question": "584)\uf020 Who won 2019 FIFA best player women's award",
    "answer": "\nMegan Rapinoe of USA\n"
}{
    "question": "585)\uf020 Who won 2019 FIFA best player men's award",
    "answer": "\nLionel Messi\n"
}{
    "question": "586)\uf020 Govt launched a new health initiative named\n\u2018UMMID\u2019 for what purpose",
    "answer": " to tackle inherited\ngenetic diseases of newborn babies\n"
}{
    "question": "587)\uf020 What is the full form of UMMID",
    "answer": " Unique\nMethods of Management and treatment of\nInherited Disorders\n"
}{
    "question": "588)\uf020 India\u2019s Petronet LNG Ltd announced investment\nof $2.5 billion to acquire nearly 20 per cent equity\nstake in the Driftwood project of which country",
    "answer": "\nUSA\n"
}{
    "question": "589)\uf020 The record breaking \"Howdy Modi\" programme\nwas held at which place in Houston, USA",
    "answer": " NRG\nStadium\n"
}{
    "question": "590)\uf020 Name the world's oldest travel firm that collapsed\n(declared bankrupt) on Sep 23, stranding\nhundreds of thousands of holidaymakers around\nthe globe",
    "answer": " Thomas Cook UK\n"
}{
    "question": "591)\uf020 Name the only Indian wrestler who won silverin\nthe World Wrestling Championships held in NurSultan, Kazakhstan",
    "answer": " Deepak Punia\n"
}{
    "question": "592)\uf020 Name the star Indian boxer who created history\nby winning 1st silver medal in boxing at World\nBoxing Championship",
    "answer": " Amit Panghal\n"
}{
    "question": "593)\uf020 Which film has been selected as India\u2019s official\nentry in the International Feature Film category\nat the 92nd Academy Awards (Oscars)",
    "answer": " Gully Boy\n"
}{
    "question": "594)\uf020 Who is the director of the film Gully Boy",
    "answer": " Zoya\nAkhtar\n"
}{
    "question": "595)\uf020 Which apex energy giant plans to set up a 5-\ngigawatt solar park in Gujarat, the largest in the\ncountry",
    "answer": " National Thermal Power Corporation\nLimited (NTPC)\n"
}{
    "question": "596)\uf020 The International Day of Peace is observed\naround the world on which date",
    "answer": " September 21\n"
}{
    "question": "597)\uf020 What is the theme of this year\u2019s International Day\nof Peace",
    "answer": " Climate Action for Peace\n"
}{
    "question": "598)\uf020 The Union home ministry plans to set up\ncountry\u2019s first central police university in which\ncity",
    "answer": " Greater Noida, UP\n"
}{
    "question": "599)\uf020 Which International Day is observed on\nSeptember 18 to highlight promotion and\nconservation of bamboo industry",
    "answer": " World\nBamboo Day\n"
}{
    "question": "600)\uf020 \u2018LoktantraKeSwar\u2019 and The Republican Ethic, both\nthe books are a compilation of speeches of which\nIndian statesman",
    "answer": " President Ram Nath Kovind\n"
}{
    "question": "601)\uf020 The 25th Senior Women\u2019s National Football\nChampionship was held in which city",
    "answer": " Pasighat\nin Arunachal Pradesh\n"
}{
    "question": "603)\uf020 Millions of people around the world observed\nglobal climate strike on Sep 20, inspired by\nSwedish student activist. What is her name",
    "answer": "\nGreta Thunberg\n"
}{
    "question": "604)\uf020 In a major bonanza for corporates as part of\nmeasures to promote growth and investment, on\nSep 20 Finance Minister announced to slash\ncorporate tax rate from 30 percent to ______\npercent for domestic companies ",
    "answer": "22\n"
}{
    "question": "605)\uf020 Vinod Kumar Yadav, Chairman of Railway Board\nwas honoured with the Eminent Engineers Award\non which special occasion",
    "answer": " 52nd Engineers\u2019 Day\n"
}{
    "question": "606)\uf020 Name the American breast cancer survivor who\nbecame the first person to swim across the\nEnglish Channel four times in a non-stop 54-hour\nfeat of endurance",
    "answer": " Sarah Thomas\n"
}{
    "question": "607)\uf020 South Asia\u2019s tallest tower, standing 350 meter\nhigh, was thrown open to public in Colombo, Sri\nLanka. What is it\u2019s name",
    "answer": " \u2018Lotus Tower\u2019\n"
}{
    "question": "608)\uf020 What is the name of the mascot of the 2022\nBeijing Winter Olympics",
    "answer": " Bing DwenDwen\n"
}{
    "question": "609)\uf020 The mascot Bing DwenDwen has been created\nbased on which animal",
    "answer": " A chubby giant Panda\n"
}{
    "question": "610)\uf020 The public sector banks have been asked to hold\nspecial public meetings for loan disbursals to the\nMSME sector in how many districts",
    "answer": " 400\n"
}{
    "question": "611)\uf020 Who will be the next chief of Indian Air force wef\nSep 30, 2019 in the rank of Air Chief Marshal",
    "answer": " Air\nMarshal Rakesh Kumar Singh Bhadauria\n"
}{
    "question": "612)\uf020 Who became India's first female military diplomat\nto be posted in any of the Indian missions abroad",
    "answer": "\nWing Commander Anjali Singh\n"
}{
    "question": "613)\uf020 Who is the current President of the World Bank",
    "answer": "\nDavid Malpass\n"
}{
    "question": "614)\uf020 India formally launched an initiative to fund 1,000\nscholars from which group of countries to pursue \nGYANM GENERAL AWARENESS \u2013FEBRUARY 2020 95\nPhD at its 23 IITs",
    "answer": " ASEAN (Association of\nSoutheast Asian Nations)\n"
}{
    "question": "615)\uf020 Which global organization has decided to\ntranslate and publish an anthology of the writings\nof Guru Nanak Dev Ji in world languages to mark\nhis 550th birth anniversary",
    "answer": " The United Nations\nEducational, Scientific and Cultural\nOrganization (UNESCO)\n"
}{
    "question": "616)\uf020 The 20th IIFA awards ceremony was held on Sep\n18 for the first time in India, in which city",
    "answer": "\nMumbai\n"
}{
    "question": "617)\uf020 Who won the International Indian Film Academy\n(IIFA) Best Director award for the film\nAndhadhun",
    "answer": " Sriram Raghavan\n"
}{
    "question": "618)\uf020 Which film won the IIFA award for the best film",
    "answer": "\nRaazi by Meghna Gulzar\n"
}{
    "question": "619)\uf020 What is the approved strength of the judges\n(including Chief Justice) in the Supreme Court",
    "answer": " 34\n"
}{
    "question": "620)\uf020 What is the category of the fighter air craft Tejas",
    "answer": "\nLight Combat Aircraft - LCA\n"
}{
    "question": "622)\uf020 Finance Minister recently announced that the\ngovernment has decided to put a complete ban on\nwhich type of cigarettes",
    "answer": " E-cigarettes\n"
}{
    "question": "623)\uf020 Country wise, the _____ is home to the largest\nnumber of migrants (5.1 crore)",
    "answer": " USA\n"
}{
    "question": "624)\uf020 Which state launched the MukhyamantriSeva\nSankalp Helpline number \u20181100\u2019 to provide timely\nhelp to the residents of the state",
    "answer": " Himachal\nPradesh\n"
}{
    "question": "625)\uf020 What is the full form of \u201cNIRVIK\u201d, export credit\ninsurance scheme ",
    "answer": "Niryat Rin Vikas Yojana\n"
}{
    "question": "626)\uf020 India\u2019s first National Antimicrobial Resistance\n(AMR) Hub was inaugurated in which city",
    "answer": "\nKolkata\n"
}{
    "question": "627)\uf020 A documentary film titled \u2018____\u2019, based on the life\nof a Uttarakhand farmer, has been nominated for\nOscars",
    "answer": " Moti Bagh\n"
}{
    "question": "628)\uf020 Mayank Vaidhas become the first Indian origin\nperson to complete which triathlon in a new\nrecord time",
    "answer": " Enduroman\n"
}{
    "question": "629)\uf020 What are the three physical activities included in\nthe Enduroman triathlon",
    "answer": " Running, Swimming\nand Cycling\n"
}{
    "question": "630)\uf020 Which country lifted the Basketball World Cup\nheld in Beijing, China",
    "answer": " Spain\n"
}{
    "question": "631)\uf020 Name the film that became the only Indian film to\nfeature in \u201cThe Guardian\u201d list of the 100 Best\nFilms of the 21st century",
    "answer": " Gangs of Wasseypur\n"
}{
    "question": "632)\uf020 Who is the director of the film \u201cGangs of\nWasseypur\u201d",
    "answer": " Anurag Kashyap\n"
}{
    "question": "633)\uf020 Name the country's official mapping agency that\nhas decided to use, for the first time, drones to\nmap the country",
    "answer": " Survey of India\n"
}{
    "question": "634)\uf020 DrKalam Smriti International Excellence Award2019 was recently conferred upon Prime Minister\nof which country",
    "answer": " Bangladesh\n"
}{
    "question": "635)\uf020 The World Ozone Day is observed on which day of\nSeptember",
    "answer": " 16 September\n"
}{
    "question": "636)\uf020 What is the theme for this year\u2019s World Ozone\nDay",
    "answer": " 32 Years and Healing\n"
}{
    "question": "637)\uf020 Name the star Indian cueist who clinched a record\n22nd world title by winning the IBSF World\nBilliards Championship",
    "answer": " Pankaj Advani\n"
}{
    "question": "638)\uf020 Which apex Indian broadcasting organization\ncelebrated on September 15 it\u2019s 60 years of\nexistence",
    "answer": " Doordarshan\n"
}{
    "question": "639)\uf020 Union Finance Minister announced a set of\nmeasures to boost the _____ sector in the form of\nprovision of Rs 50,000 crore for various\nincentives",
    "answer": " Export\n"
}{
    "question": "640)\uf020 India celebrates the Engineer\u2019s Day on which\ndate",
    "answer": " September 15\n"
}{
    "question": "641)\uf020 The Engineer\u2019s Day is observed to mark the birth\nanniversary of which acclaimed civil engineer",
    "answer": "\nBharat RatnaM Visvesvaraya\n"
}{
    "question": "642)\uf020 Lakshya Sen who won the Belgian International\nChallenge in Leuven, Belgium is associated with\nwhich sport",
    "answer": " Badminton\n"
}{
    "question": "643)\uf020 Name the star Indian Badminton player who\nclinched the Vietnam Open Super 100 badminton\ntitle",
    "answer": " Saurabh Verma\n"
}{
    "question": "644)\uf020 Around the world International Democracy Day is\nobserved on which day",
    "answer": " September 15\n"
}{
    "question": "645)\uf020 The DRDO handed over the second Airborne Early\nWarning and Control (AEWC) aircraft to the\nIndian Air Force. Name the aircraft",
    "answer": " Netra\n"
}{
    "question": "646)\uf020 According to World University Ranking\n2020released by Times Higher Education society\non September 11 _______ university secured top\nrank for the 4th successive year",
    "answer": " Oxford\n"
}{
    "question": "647)\uf020 Government plans to establish Indian Institute of\nSkills (IIS) at ______ to provide skill training in\nhighly-specialised areas to students",
    "answer": " Mumbai\n"
}{
    "question": "648)\uf020 Govt. announced that on Gandhi Jayanti, 1,070\nspecial courts will be set up all over the country\nfor dealing with POCSO cases. This relates to\nwhich type of cases",
    "answer": " Sexual offences against\nwomen and children\n"
}{
    "question": "649)\uf020 On which railway station railways have\nestablished their first ever fun zone",
    "answer": "\nVisakhapatnam\n"
}{
    "question": "650)\uf020 Name the senior bureaucrat who has been\nappointed as the Principal Advisor to Prime\nMinister",
    "answer": " Pradeep Kumar Sinha\n"
}{
    "question": "651)\uf020 ______ became the first Asiannation to unveil plain\ncigarette packaging to reduce the appeal of\nsmoking and to comply with the WHO guidelines",
    "answer": "\nThailand\n"
}{
    "question": "652)\uf020 ________ became the first country in 2012 to \nGYANM GENERAL AWARENESS \u2013FEBRUARY 2020 96\nrequire tobacco products to be sold without\ncolourful brand logos",
    "answer": " Australia\n"
}{
    "question": "653)\uf020 In the history of Indian Railways, for the first\ntime, a train will not be operated by the Railways.\nName this train",
    "answer": "Tejas Express\n"
}{
    "question": "654)\uf020 Indian Railways has outsourced running of the\nTejas Express to which agency",
    "answer": " IRCTC\n"
}{
    "question": "655)\uf020 What is the full form of IRCTC",
    "answer": " Indian Railway\nCatering and Tourism Corporation\n"
}{
    "question": "656)\uf020 The DDCA (Delhi and Districts Cricket\nAssociation) unveiled a new pavilion stand named\nafter which cricketer in theArun Jaitley Cricket\nStadium in New Delhi",
    "answer": " Virat Kohli\n"
}{
    "question": "657)\uf020 The Centre has finalised the site for a 7,500 MW\nmega solar project at which place in Ladakh\nregion",
    "answer": " Pang\n"
}{
    "question": "658)\uf020 Nationwide mass campaign against the use of\n\u2018single use plastics\u2019 was launched from Mathura.\nWhat is its name",
    "answer": " Swachhta hi Seva 2019\n"
}{
    "question": "659)\uf020 Dr. Pramod Kumar Mishra has been appointed as\nthe _________ to the Prime Minister",
    "answer": " Principal\nSecretary\n"
}{
    "question": "660)\uf020 Niti Aayog has selected which global management\nconsultancy to set up India\u2019s first Digital\nCapability Centre",
    "answer": " McKinsey & Company\n"
}{
    "question": "661)\uf020 National Animal Disease Control Programme was\nlaunched from ______ in Uttar Pradesh",
    "answer": " Mathura\n"
}{
    "question": "662)\uf020 What was the name of one of the strongest storms\nto hit Tokyo in the last several years, with winds\nof up to 210km/h",
    "answer": " Typhoon Faxai\n"
}{
    "question": "663)\uf020 India\u2019s second riverine Multi Modal Terminal was\ninaugurated at Sahibganj on River Ganga in which\nstate",
    "answer": " Jharkhand\n"
}{
    "question": "664)\uf020 India's first multi modal terminal was opened up\nin Nov 2018 at which place",
    "answer": " Varanasi\n"
}{
    "question": "665)\uf020 Bharti Airtel launched which new broadband\nservice that will offer a speed of 1 Gbps for Rs.\n3,999 a month",
    "answer": " AirtelXstreamFibre\n"
}{
    "question": "666)\uf020 Name the noted golfer from Ireland who was\nnamed the PGA Tour Player of the Year for a third\ntime",
    "answer": " Rory McIlroy\n"
}{
    "question": "667)\uf020 Name the Indian cyclist who won four golds in the\nTrack Asia Cup cycling championship in New\nDelhi",
    "answer": " Ronaldo Laitonjam\n"
}{
    "question": "668)\uf020 DRDO successfully flight tested indigenously\ndeveloped MPATGM in Kurnool, Andhra Pradesh.\nExpand the term MPATGM",
    "answer": " Man Portable Antitank Guided Missile\n"
}{
    "question": "669)\uf020 Ministry of Agriculture launched a multilingual\nmobile app 'CHC Farm Machinery' to allow\nfarmers to hire farm equipment locally. Here CHC\nstands for what",
    "answer": " Custom Hiring Service Centres\n"
}{
    "question": "670)\uf020 Indian Prime Minister crossed the mark of 50\nmillion followers on his twitter account, becoming\nthe third most followed world leader. Who is the\nfirst ranked leader with 108.2 million followers",
    "answer": "\nBarack Obama\n"
}{
    "question": "671)\uf020 World Suicide Prevention Day observed on\nSeptember 10 is supported by which UN\norganization",
    "answer": " WHO-World Health Organization\n"
}{
    "question": "672)\uf020 South Asia\u2019s first cross-border petroleum pipeline\nwas inaugurated between which two countries",
    "answer": "\nIndiaand Nepal\n"
}{
    "question": "673)\uf020 Government has set up a three-member panel\nheaded by former Defence Secretary Sanjay Mitra\nfor what purpose",
    "answer": " To oversee the bifurcation of\nJammu and Kashmir into two Union\nTerritories\n"
}{
    "question": "674)\uf020 The Indian Air Force (IAF) recreated its 17\nSquadron 'Golden Arrows' based at which Air\nForce Station",
    "answer": " Ambala Cantt, Haryana\n"
}{
    "question": "675)\uf020 The recently formed 17 Squadron 'Golden\nArrows' is likely to fly which air craft",
    "answer": " Rafale\nfighter jet\n"
}{
    "question": "676)\uf020 Charles Leclerc won the Italian Grand Prix at\nMonza, Italy. What is this sport",
    "answer": " F1 car racing\n"
}{
    "question": "677)\uf020 What is the name of the highest marathon in the\nworld, held at over 11,000 feet above the mean\nsea level",
    "answer": " Ladakh Marathon\n"
}{
    "question": "678)\uf020 Asian Development Bank approved a $ 200\nmillion loan for upgrading rural roads in 34\ndistricts of _____ to improve road safety",
    "answer": "\nMaharashtra\n"
}{
    "question": "679)\uf020 Which payment bank recently launched Aadhaar\nEnabled Payment System (AEPS) Services for\nexpanding access to financial services for millions\nof unbanked and underbanked customers",
    "answer": " India\nPost Payments Bank\n"
}{
    "question": "680)\uf020 Name the player who won the Men's single titles\nof the US Open Grand Slam",
    "answer": " Rafael Nadal\n"
}{
    "question": "681)\uf020 Name the 19 year old Canadian girl who won the\nWomen's singles title of the US Open Grand Slam",
    "answer": "\nBianca Andreescu\n"
}{
    "question": "682)\uf020 Which awards are popularly known as \"Oscars of\nScience\"",
    "answer": " Breakthrough prizes\n"
}{
    "question": "683)\uf020 The Breakthrough prizes are given in how many\nfields",
    "answer": " 3\n"
}{
    "question": "684)\uf020 Name the 3 fields in which Breakthrough Prizes\nare given",
    "answer": " Fundamental Physics, Life Sciences\nand Mathematics\n"
}{
    "question": "685)\uf020 Each Breakthrough Prize carries an award of\nwhat amount",
    "answer": " $3 million\n"
}{
    "question": "686)\uf020 As per the World Travel & Tourism\nCompetitiveness Index 2019 released by the\nWorld Economic Forum (WEF), India has jumped\n6 places to claim which spot",
    "answer": " 34th\n"
}{
    "question": "687)\uf020 Which country was placed at no. 1 spot in the\nWorld Travel & Tourism Competitiveness Index\n2019",
    "answer": " Spain\n"
}{
    "question": "688)\uf020 Rohit Sharma, Indian Cricket team vice-captain\nlaunched \u201cRohit4Rhinos\u201d campaign. They are the\n\"state animal\" of which state",
    "answer": " Assam\nGYANM GENERAL AWARENESS \u2013FEBRUARY 2020 97\n"
}{
    "question": "689)\uf020 Which Indian state signed an MoU for sister state\nwith the Delaware State of America",
    "answer": " Gujarat\n"
}{
    "question": "690)\uf020 What was the name of the annual Joint IndoLanka maritime fleet exercise that was held off\nthe coast of Visakhapatnam",
    "answer": " SLINEX 2019\n"
}{
    "question": "691)\uf020 In an official survey to select the best \u2018Swachh\nIconic Place\u2019 in the country, which place was\nadjudged as the \"Best Swachh Iconic place\"",
    "answer": " Shri\nMata Vaishno Devi Shrine near Katra, Jammu\n"
}{
    "question": "692)\uf020 The Indian Army has announced that the first\nbatch of 100 women soldiers will be\ncommissioned by March 2021. They will join\nwhich corps",
    "answer": " Corps of Military Police\n"
}{
    "question": "693)\uf020 Exercise \"YudhAbhyas 2019\" was held between\narmy units of India and which other country",
    "answer": " USA\n"
}{
    "question": "694)\uf020 Exercise \"YudhAbhyas 2019\" was held at which\nplace",
    "answer": " Washington, USA\n"
}{
    "question": "695)\uf020 The RBI has made it mandatory for banks to link\ninterest on all their new loan products to which\npolicy rate of RBI",
    "answer": " Repo Rate\n"
}{
    "question": "696)\uf020 The official logo of Qatar 2022 FIFA world cup is\nbased on 3D version of which arithmetical\nsymbol",
    "answer": " Infinity\n"
}{
    "question": "697)\uf020 Which city in USA hosted the second edition of the\nJaipur Literature Festival on September 13-14",
    "answer": "\nHouston\n"
}{
    "question": "698)\uf020 Name the India\u2019s Chief Election Commissioner\nwho has been elected the Chairman of Association\nof World Election Bodies",
    "answer": " Sunil Arora\n"
}{
    "question": "699)\uf020 The 20th India-Russia Annual Summit was held in\nwhich city",
    "answer": " Vladivostok\n"
}{
    "question": "700)\uf020 Which Indian Cricketer recently broke MS Dhoni\u2019s\nwicket-keeping record for India by becoming the\nfastest Indian wicket-keeper to claim 50\ndismissals in Test cricket",
    "answer": " Rishabh Pant\n"
}{
    "question": "701)\uf020 From September 1,govt. has imposed steep hike\nin the traffic violation fines. Which act has been\namended for this purpose",
    "answer": " Motor Vehicles Act\n2019\n"
}{
    "question": "702)\uf020 According to a \"Global Happiness Survey\" by\nIpsos, Indian has been ranked ______on the\nhappiness index",
    "answer": " 9th\n"
}{
    "question": "703)\uf020 As per the \"Global Happiness Survey\" by Ipsos,\nwhich two countries have been ranked as the\nhappiest in the World",
    "answer": " Australia and Canada\n"
}{
    "question": "704)\uf020 Virat Kohli surpassed which cricketer to become\nIndia\u2019s most successful captain in test matches",
    "answer": "\nMahendra Singh Dhoni\n"
}{
    "question": "705)\uf020 Bill & Melinda Gates Foundation honored which\nIndian statesman for his outstanding work in the\nSwachh Bharat Abhiyan",
    "answer": " Prime Minister\nNarendra Modi\n"
}{
    "question": "706)\uf020 India\u2019s is planning to explore the deep sea region\nwith which project by 2021-22",
    "answer": " 'Samudrayaan'\n"
}{
    "question": "707)\uf020 The highest sky cycling track of the country has\nbeen built at an altitude of 9,000 feet in which\nstate",
    "answer": " Himachal Pradesh\n"
}{
    "question": "708)\uf020 Indian Institute of Petroleum has set up a plant in\n_______ that can turn plastic waste into diesel",
    "answer": "\nDehradun\n"
}{
    "question": "709)\uf020 Which state launched its exclusive 24x7 education\nchannel 'KalviTholaikkatchi' for school students\nof classes I to XII",
    "answer": " Tamil Nadu\n"
}{
    "question": "710)\uf020 HRD ministry launched one of the world\u2019s largest\nIntegrated Online Junction for School Education\nnamed ______ in New Delhi",
    "answer": " \u2018Shagun\u2019\n"
}{
    "question": "711)\uf020 Dindigul locks and Kandangi sarees of which state\nhave been granted Geographical Indication (GI)\ntags",
    "answer": " Tamil Nadu\n"
}{
    "question": "712)\uf020 The DeendayalAntyodaya Yojana- NULM won the\nSKOCH Governance Gold Award 2019. What is the\nfull form of NULM",
    "answer": " National Urban Livelihoods\nMission\n"
}{
    "question": "713)\uf020 Which state launched the \u2018Walk to Work\u2019\ncampaign in the state as a part of \u2018Fit India\nMovement\u2019 launched in the country by the Prime\nMinister",
    "answer": " Meghalaya\n"
}{
    "question": "714)\uf020 V K Johri, senior IPS officer has been appointed as\nthe new Director General of which para-military\nforce",
    "answer": " Border Security Force (BSF)\n"
}{
    "question": "715)\uf020 Which country lifted the SAFF Under-15 Football\ntitle at Kolkata, West Bengal with a 7-0 win over\nNepal",
    "answer": " India\n"
}{
    "question": "716)\uf020 Who has been appointed as the new Governor of\nMaharashtra",
    "answer": " Bhagat Singh Koshyari\n"
}{
    "question": "717)\uf020 Arif Mohammed Khan has been made Governor of\nwhich southern state",
    "answer": " Kerala\n"
}{
    "question": "718)\uf020 What is the name of the new Governor of\nRajasthan",
    "answer": " Kalraj Mishra\n"
}{
    "question": "719)\uf020 Name the former union minister who now is the\nGovernor of Himachal Pradesh",
    "answer": "\nBandaruDattatreya\n"
}{
    "question": "720)\uf020 Name the lady who has been appointed the\nGovernor of Telangana",
    "answer": " Dr Ms. T Soundararajan\n"
}{
    "question": "721)\uf020 What is the full form of \u2018POSHAN\u2019",
    "answer": " Prime\nMinister's Overreaching Scheme for Holistic\nNourishment\n"
}{
    "question": "722)\uf020 India recently hosted the 4th Conference of\nParties, COP14 to the UNCCD at which place",
    "answer": "\nGreater Noida, UP\n"
}{
    "question": "723)\uf020 What is the full form of UNCCD",
    "answer": " United\nNationsConvention to Combat Desertification\n"
}{
    "question": "724)\uf020 Prime Minister Narendra Modi launched which\ncampaign to promote fitness on National Sports\nDay - August 29",
    "answer": " 'Fit India Movement'\n"
}{
    "question": "725)\uf020 The U.S. President announced the formation\nof which new space force that will combine skills\nand assets from all U.S. military branches",
    "answer": " \u201cSpace\nCommand\u201d or SpaceCom\n"
}{
    "question": "726)\uf020 Name the teenage climate campaigner school girl\nfrom Sweden who sailed from UK to New York on\na zero-emissions yacht to highlight the ecological \nGYANM GENERAL AWARENESS \u2013FEBRUARY 2020 98\ncrisis earth is facing because of climate change",
    "answer": "\nGreta Thunberg\n"
}{
    "question": "727)\uf020 The total horticulture production in the country, ,\nis estimated to be around",
    "answer": " 313million tones\n"
}{
    "question": "728)\uf020 Which Indian airline has announced to completely\nban the use of plastic in it\u2019s catering operations",
    "answer": "\nAir India\n"
}{
    "question": "729)\uf020 The government announced the merger of ten\npublic sector banks into four banks. Now how\nmany public sector banks will be there",
    "answer": " 12\n"
}{
    "question": "730)\uf020 Which two banks will now be merged with the\nPunjab National Bank",
    "answer": " Oriental Bank of\nCommerce and United Bank\n"
}{
    "question": "731)\uf020 As per recent announcement by the Finance\nMinister, which bank will be merged with Canara\nBank",
    "answer": " Syndicate Bank\n"
}{
    "question": "732)\uf020 Government has decided to merge which bank\nwith the Indian Bank",
    "answer": " Allahabad Bank\n"
}{
    "question": "733)\uf020 Under the recently announced bank merger plan,\nwhich two banks are to be merged with the Union\nBank of India",
    "answer": " Andhra Bank and Corporation\nBank\n"
}{
    "question": "734)\uf020 The Union Cabinet recently approved 100 percent\nFDI under automatic route in which two sectors",
    "answer": "\nCoal mining and in contract manufacturing\n"
}{
    "question": "735)\uf020 Which European country has decided to reduce\nthe country's parliament by 25 per cent as part of\nan overhaul of the country's institutions",
    "answer": " France\n"
}{
    "question": "736)\uf020 India recently started a new bus service from\nSiliguri in West Bengal to which place",
    "answer": "\nKathmandu\n"
}{
    "question": "737)\uf020 India has become the first country in the world to\nissue a Biometric Seafarer Identity Document.\nWhat is the common word for Seafarer",
    "answer": " Sailors\nAUGUST - 2019\n"
}